Guide to the Ithaca Festival records, 1962-1984.
Ithaca Festival records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca Festival records, 1962-1984.
2593
1.8 cubic ft., 29 tapes, 38 transcripts.
Printed Materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records concerning the organization and development of the Festival include agendas and minutes of the Board of Trustees and the Executive; minutes and reports of various other committees; fund raising and public relations consultants' reports, the report on a space and accommodation program prepared by Fairchild and Dubois, Toronto architects, and a statement on the Festival by the Department of Speech and Drama at Cornell University; correspondence, memoranda, resolutions, financial statements, and rough notes; four versions of a promotional brochure outlining the purpose of the Festival, giving information on the major figures concerned and on the size and geographical distribution of the potential audience, projecting estimates of revenue and expenses for a typical season, and including a section by Alan Schneider entitled "The Idea of a Festival Theatre in Ithaca..." and a file of correspondence, minutes, and memoranda pertaining to the earlier organization; an incomplete run (1965-1966) of the newsletter "From the Wings," newspaper clippings, and other printed matter.
Also, tapes and transcripts (1965-1971) of the Cornell University Oral History Program's Ithaca Festival Documentation Project conducted by Marian Hodges, Gould Colman, Katrina Morse, David Harry Watrous Smith, Edwina Devereux, and Edward Devereux, including interviews with Kit Boynton, Walter G. Bruska, Ralph N. Campbell, Marvin A. Carlson, William R. Carpenter, Joseph F. Daine, Edwina Devereux, Howard I. Dillingham, Leonard Edelstein, Henry Guerlac, Francine Herman, Mary W. John, Jean F. Lynch, Beatrice MacLeod, Steven Muller, Thomas Niederkorn, Norbert H. Schickel, Jr., William F. Schmidt, Alan Scneider, Randall E. Shew, John Summerskill, Charles Treman Jr., and Walter Wiggins, mainly concerning their interest in and support for the Ithaca Festival, but also referring to Summer-Ithaca, and an interview with J. Wesley Zeigler concerning his role as manageing director. Among the other persons represented in these records are David Ketchum, Robert Mueller, Leverett Saltonstall, Jr., and Alvin H. Reiss.
The Ithaca Festival (previously Summer-Ithaca and the Ithaca Festival of the Classics) incorporated in 1964 as a center for the performing arts in Ithaca and Tompkins County, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records concerning the organization and development of the Festival include agendas and minutes of the Board of Trustees and the Executive; minutes and reports of various other committees; fund raising and public relations consultants' reports, the report on a space and accommodation program prepared by Fairchild and Dubois, Toronto architects, and a statement on the Festival by the Department of Speech and Drama at Cornell University; correspondence, memoranda, resolutions, financial statements, and rough notes; four versions of a promotional brochure outlining the purpose of the Festival, giving information on the major figures concerned and on the size and geographical distribution of the potential audience, projecting estimates of revenue and expenses for a typical season, and including a section by Alan Schneider entitled "The Idea of a Festival Theatre in Ithaca..." and a file of correspondence, minutes, and memoranda pertaining to the earlier organization; an incomplete run (1965-1966) of the newsletter "From the Wings," newspaper clippings, and other printed matter.
Also, tapes and transcripts (1965-1971) of the Cornell University Oral History Program's Ithaca Festival Documentation Project conducted by Marian Hodges, Gould Colman, Katrina Morse, David Harry Watrous Smith, Edwina Devereux, and Edward Devereux, including interviews with Kit Boynton, Walter G. Bruska, Ralph N. Campbell, Marvin A. Carlson, William R. Carpenter, Joseph F. Daine, Edwina Devereux, Howard I. Dillingham, Leonard Edelstein, Henry Guerlac, Francine Herman, Mary W. John, Jean F. Lynch, Beatrice MacLeod, Steven Muller, Thomas Niederkorn, Norbert H. Schickel, Jr., William F. Schmidt, Alan Scneider, Randall E. Shew, John Summerskill, Charles Treman Jr., and Walter Wiggins, mainly concerning their interest in and support for the Ithaca Festival, but also referring to Summer-Ithaca, and an interview with J. Wesley Zeigler concerning his role as manageing director. Among the other persons represented in these records are David Ketchum, Robert Mueller, Leverett Saltonstall, Jr., and Alvin H. Reiss.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Boynton, Kit.; Bruska, Walter G.; Campbell, Ralph N.; Carlson, Marvin, 1935-; Carpenter, William R.; Daino, Joseph F.; Devereux, Edwina.; Dillingham, Howard I.; Edelstein, Leonard.; Guerlac, Henry.; Herman, Francine.; John, Mary W.; Ketchum, David.; Lynch, Jean F.; MacLeod, Beatrice.; Mueller, Robert.; Muller, Steven.; Niederkorn, Thomas.; Reiss, Alvin H.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979.; Schickel, Norbert H., Jr.; Schmidt, William F.; Schneider, Alan, 1917-1984.; Shew, Randall E.; Summerskill, John.; Treman, Charles, Jr.; Wiggins, Walter J.; Zeigler, J. Wesley.; Boynton, Kit; Bruska, Walter G.; Campbell, Ralph N.; Carlson, Marvin, 1935-; Carpenter, William R.; Daino, Joseph F.; Devereux, Edwina; Dillingham, Howard I.; Edelstein, Leonard; Guerlac, Henry; Herman, Francine; John, Mary W.; Ketchum, David; Lynch, Jean F.; MacLeod, Beatrice; Mueller, Robert; Muller, Steven; Niederkorn, Thomas; Reiss, Alvin H.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979; Schickel, Norbert H., Jr.; Schmidt, William F.; Schneider, Alan, 1917-1984; Shew, Randall E.; Summerskill, John; Treman, Charles, Jr; Wiggins, Walter J.; Zeigler, J. Wesley; Colman, Gould P. (Gould Patchin), 1926-; Devereux, Edward.; Devereux, Edwina.; Hodges, Marian.; Morse, Katrina.; Smith, David Harry Watrous.; Cornell University. Department of Speech and Drama.; Fairfield and Dubois.
Titles:
From the wings.
Subjects:
Art festivals.; Art festivals
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.) -- Festivals, etc.; New York (State) -- Ithaca
Form and Genre Terms:
Oral histories.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Tapes and transcripts restricted to permission of the archivist.
SERIES LIST
Series I. DVDs
Series II. CD-Rs
Series III. Videos
Series IV. Other Materials
CONTAINER LIST
- DVDs
  - Ithaca Festival, Image DVD, 2008-06-19; DVD-3358; Reis, Jon (Box 4)
    426 images, 4x6@300ppi; Job #020080619; Client: Jake Roberts
  - Paint Off, 2011-04; DVD-3359 (Box 4)
  - Parade, Undated; DVD-3360 (Box 4)
- CD-Rs
  - Ithaca Festival panoramas - Disc 1, 2011-01; CD-4981 (Box 4)
  - Viewing photos, 2005-07-01; CD-4982; Reis, Jon (Box 4)
    Client: Ithaca Festival
  - Erika pics, Undated; CD-4983 (Box 4)
  - Festival 2009 Paint-A-Thon, 2009; CD-4984; Markle, Robin (Box 4)
    247 images, 4x6@300ppi; Job: C.N060601-04; Client: Vicki Kysar
  - Ithaca Festival 2006, 2006-04; CD-4985 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival 2011 Program, 2011; CD-4986 (Box 4)
  - Demo, Undated; CD-4987; Jen Cork and the Good Hope (Box 4)
  - Image CD, 2006-04-26; CD-4988 (Box 4)
    4x6@300ppi; Job: CN050602; Client: Vicki Kysar, Ithaca Festival Office
  - Ithaca Festival panoramas - Disc 3, 2003-07-31; CD-4989 (Box 4)
    22-31
  - Ithaca Festival panoramas - Disc 2, 2003-07-31; CD-4990 (Box 4)
    21-Dec
  - Itahca Festival slides and panoramas for web, 2003-07-31; CD-4991 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival panoramas and slides - Disc 4, 2003-07-31; CD-4992 (Box 4)
    32-35 pan, 36-40 slidees
  - Ithaca Fest 2005, 2005; CD-4993 (Box 4)
- Videos
  - Ithaca Festival, 1979; V-11577 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival master, 1980-06-14-1980-06-18; V-11578 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1981; V-11579 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1981; V-11580 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1982; V-11581-11583 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1983; V-11584 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1986; V-11585-11586 (Box 3)
  - Ithaca Festival, 1988; V-11587-11588 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival Higlights, 1989; V-11589-11591 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival Higlights, 1998; V-11592 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival, 2000; V-11593 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival - Circus Eccentrithaca, 2001-06-03; V-11594 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival - Circus Eccentrithaca, 2001-06-03; V-11595 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival parade and cable cast, 1999; V-11596 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival parade, Undated; V-11597 (Box 4)
  - Channel 7 - Ithaca Festival Press Conference, 2001-02; V-11598 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival commercial, 1999; V-11599 (Box 4)
  - Ithaca Festival Promo, 2001; V-11600-11601 (Box 3)
- Other Materials
  - Newspapers, 2006-2012 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Video content lists, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1995-2011 (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
  - Brochures, 2001-2011 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Assorted flyers and clippings, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Text printouts, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bread and puppet, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Slides, Date Unknown (Box 4, Folder 10)